

JIM COURTOIS

314.677.0911

thatonejimguy@gmail.com www.thatonejimguy.com

**OBJECTIVE** 

Seeking a full-time creative position consistent with my passion for digital-focused design.

**ABOUT** 

I am a St. Louis Native with over 7 years of experience in design. The bulk of my career has been spent as an in-house designer working on building brands. Over the last several years, I have been focused almost completely on designing for the digital space. In particular, I love creating mobile-first websites using Twitter Bootstrap and designing mobile applications for iOS and Android. I pride myself on my style of artful design with the technicical approach of a developer.

# Photoshop • HTML • Wordpress • Illustrator • CSS • Print production • InDesign • jQuery • Motion Design • Acrobat • Bootstrap • Digital photography • Microsoft Office • Git repos • Video production

## FINE SKILLS

- Brand identity
- Complex problem solving
- · Clever responsive layouts
- Project organization
- Digital illustration
- Idea generation
- Intuitive mobile UX
- Brand strategy
- Creative copywriting
- Traditional illustration

**EDUCATION** 

Bachelor of Arts in Advertising & Media – 2010, Lindenwood University, St. Charles, MO
Associate of Fine Arts in Graphic Design – 2007, Saint Louis Community College, St. Louis, MO

### **EXPERIENCE**

Lead Designer // Rover Enterprises, LLC // March 2014 - Current

My main responsibility is the ongoing design and UX for two extensive mobile applications: "RoverTown Student Discounts" and "RoverTown for Business." I also create and develop the front-end of corporate web assets and applications, as well as a full range of printed marketing materials. I am essential to company strategy and idea generation. Other duties include digital illustration, managing one other designer, and extensive creative copywriting.

# Freelance Designer // McCord Design Group, Fish Window Cleaning // December 2013 - March 2014

I completed a one month contract as an in-office freelancer for McCord Design Group in Kirkwood, MO. I also completed various small projects off-site for Fish Window Cleaning. My freelancing stopped when I started at RoverTown.

# Brand Manager // Dover Enterprises, LLC // April 2011 - November 2013

I designed a white-label daily deals platform, including a web and mobile app, called "Groupigg." I developed the Groupigg brand. I created the Dealpigg brand from scratch based on Groupigg. I was responsible for all web and print materials for internal and external use in addition to managing the production of daily deal editorials, overseeing social media properties, as well as light creative copywriting. I was laid off after the daily deal bubble burst and the company was liquidated.

# In-house Graphic Designer // Fish Window Cleaning Services, Inc. // November 2009 – April 2011

I worked directly with the executive committee in the corporate HQ to create and deliver FISH branding initiatives at the national level, including b2b and consumer marketing materials, product design, vehicle graphics, and more. I created all marketing materials for the franchise sales department. I also provided custom design support to 180 FISH franchisees across 42 states. I left due to creative differences and finding a better fit in a position with more autonomy.

# Production Artist // JWT Specialized Communications // August 2007 – November 2009

I worked on a small production team that handled a weekly flow of 100-200 newspaper and magazine ads created according to strict styleguides. Our department had 31 sets of client styleguides. I was often assigned other projects including new template creation, photo retouching and internal print projects. I was laid off during the 2009 Recession.